Zachary Harwood

516-902-9766 | 320zach@gmail.com | Rochester, NY

Summary

Driven and efficient problem solver with six years of experience in web and application development, UI/UX, and usability-focused design

Skills

Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Git, JQuery, AngularJS, Web Development, Software development, Application Development, Unity, Swift, Figma, Node.is, Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Project Management

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY MS, Human Computer Interaction | 05/2024 Graduated — 3.8 GPA

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY BS, New media interactive development | 05/2020

· Graduated cum laude

Experience

Jewish Play Project | Rochester, NY UI Development Intern | 05/2020 - 08/2020

- Updated the three main sites' UI and back-end through attention to detail and expert prioritization, resulting in an increase in web traffic by 15%
- Moved database over from a Google Form to an Airtable serve by following protocol and strong organization to optimize efficiency by 10%

City Hive

UI Development Intern | 05/2018 - 08/2018

- Increased user satisfaction by 20% through UI improvements.
- Designed a new system for viewing the customer's information client-side.
- Enhanced customer experience by developing a feature to display alcohol information across multiple merchants' sites.
- · Self-taught Angular.js in the span of two weeks

Awards

Eagle Scout - 2016

Academic projects

Project Chatboard

Lead Researcher/Developer - 2021- 2024 - Graduate thesis.

Created and tested a hypothetical communication program named Chatboard. User testing was conducted using the Figma application. Testing was performed to develop a dataset for a usability evaluation of the prototype.

Recipes at Midnight

Developer - 2019

Developed a web application by creating a custom API that stored recipe websites for ease of use while displaying data input by the user.